Guide to the School of Medicine, Yale University, Records of the Faculty and Board of Permanent Officers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
School of Medicine, Yale University, records of the faculty and board of permanent officers
1814-1960
RU 252
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2.25
The records consist of minute books from meetings of the Yale School of Medicine's faculty, its executive board, and the Committee on Examinations, and records of the Board of Permanent Officers.
Yale University. School of Medicine
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 27-C (YRG 27-C), Records of officers and faculty of the Yale School of Medicine.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the materials is partially restricted. See inventory for details.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of minute books from meetings of the Yale School of Medicine's faculty, its executive board, and the Committee on Examinations, and records of the Board of Permanent Officers.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Medical colleges -- Faculty; Medical colleges; Medicine -- Study and teaching; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Yale College (1718-1887). Medical Institution; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University. School of Medicine
- Minutes of faculty meetings, 1814-1916; Accession 1981-A-018
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  - Minutes, 1814-1916 (Box 1–2)
- Records of the Board of Permanent Officers of the Medical School, 1926-1960; Accession 1996-A-048
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2036
  - Physiology Report, 1926-1930 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Yale School of Medicine, Prudential Committee, 1936-1943 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Illegible or unidentifiable [Fulton], undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Board of Permanent Officers
    - 1938-1941 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1950 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1951 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1952 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1953 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1955 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - 1956 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - 1957 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - 1959 (Box 2, Folder 12 - 13)
    - 1960 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Minutes, 1946-1952 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - 1954 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - 1958 (Box 3, Folder 17)